In the last video we learned about the props we can output, this utility information
Sahne hakknda rendiimiz son videoda bu yardmc program bilgilerini kartabiliriz.
and regarding the history object, the utility methods even we can use to navigate around or find out where
Ve tarih nesnesi ile ilgili olarak, gezinmek veya u anda nerede olduumuzu
we are at. Now
bulmak iin kullanabileceimiz yntemler kullann.
what if we actually want to get this information not in one of our containers,
Aslnda bu bilgileri konteynrlarmzdan birinde bulamazsak ne olur?
so not in a component which was loaded through a route as defined in the blog.js file but in a component
Dolaysyla, bloun d olarak tanmland gibi bir rota yoluyla yklenmi olan bir komponentte deil,
which is rendered as part of such a container, like the Post's container. The post container is loaded
Post'un konteyneri gibi byle bir konteynrn paras olarak verilen bir komponentte,
with this route here in the blog container and the post container simply renders the post component
posta konteyneri burada bu kutu konteynrnda yklenir ve post konteyneri post bileeni
then.
basite iler.
Now if we go into that post component and for a second we turn this post component into a component
imdi post bileenine gidersek ve bir saniye iin post bileeni, aslnda J'yi u ekilde
where we actually return jsx like this.
X olarak dndrdmz bir bileene evirir.
If we dare
Cesaret edersek.
now console log the props,
imdi sahne konsolunu imzalayn.
then you will actually see that the props in the post components we see that four times because we're
Sonra aslnda greceiz ki post bileeninde sahne drt kez grdmz iin
rendering four posts is just author, clicked, title,
drt mesaj yaynlyoruz sadece tklanm bir balk sunuyor.
There is no match, location, history prop in there as we have it in the posts component, plural, not the single
Orada eleme konumu gemii pervane var biz bunu bileenleri pleuro mesajlarda
one.
tek deil.
So the routing relay the props are not passed down the component tree, we can't access them in components
Dolaysyla ynlendirme rlesi sahne alt paralar, yalnzca d paras olarak yerletirdiimiz
which we simply embed as part of the jsx code of a container.
bileenlerde eriemediimiz bileenden geirilmez. j bir kabn X kodu olarak.
Now if you wanted to use the props there, there are two ways to get access,
imdi sahne parmini kullanmak isterseniz, iki yolla eriebilirsiniz.
one of course is we can pass them on with the spread operator and this props, this passes any props
Elbette bunlar yayc operatrle geirebiliriz ve bu sahne herhangi bir sahne gereini iletir.
this post container has onto the post component.
Bu posta kutusu, posta bileenine yerletirilmitir.
Of course we could also explicitly target certain props like for example if you want to pass on the
Elbette, belirli eyalar aka hedef alabilir, rn. Eleen mlk
matched property,
gemek isterseniz.
We could also do this.props.match.
Bu sahne man da yapabiliriz.
Now this is one way of passing it on
imdi bunu gemenin bir yolu.
but there also is a higher order component we can use on the post component, there
Bununla birlikte, orada yazlan bileen zerinde kullanabileceimiz yksek dereceli bir bileen de var.
we can import something which is called withRouter from react-router-dom.
Yeniden ynlendirici ynlendirici olan Daum'dan ynlendirici ile arlan bir ieri aktarabiliriz.
Now withRouter is a higher order component which we use by wrapping our export with it, just like that.
Artk ynlendirici ile, ihracatmz bunun gibi basit bir ekilde sararak kullandmz daha yksek bir dzen unsuru var.
With this added, if we now save all files you see that now that the props are out for for the individual
Bu eklemeyle imdi tm dosyalar kaydettiysek, sahne yerlerinin ve eleme zelliklerinin bulunduu tek
posts, they do have a history location and match property.
tek yaynlar iin sahne ktna gre olduunu grrsnz.
So withRouter adds these props to other components, to any component we wrap with it.
Bylece, ynlendirici Anstey'nin Avro bileenlerini, onunla birlikte sslediimiz herhangi bir bileene yneltti.
So withRouter is a nice way of making that component route aware and it will use or it will get the props
bir yoludur ve kullanacak veya en yakn ykl rota iin bilgi ieren pervane alacak.
containing information for the nearest loaded route.
Bylece router ile dat bileeni rota farknda gzel
So in this case since post is included in posts, we get the same props as we receive in posts.
Dolaysyla bu davada yayn ilanlara dahil olduundan ilanlarda aldmzlarla ayn problar grrz.
I'm going to remove it here but this is one way for you to get access to routing related props which
Bunu buradan kaldracam ancak bu, rota Propp'u itmek veya ykl rotayla
you might need for calling push on the history prop or for getting information about the loaded route.
ilgili bilgi almak iin ihtiyacnz olabilecek rota ile ilgili pervane eriimini salamanzn bir yoludur.
This is one way of getting access
Bu, ulamann bir yoludur.
using this approach of accessing props with the higher order component here.
Buraya yksek mertebeden bileenlerle erimenin bu yaklamn kullanarak.
Now again I'm removing it here
imdi tekrar buradan kaldryorum.
so I'm going back to the original state for my post component.
Bu yzden post bileeni iin orijinal durumuna geri dnyorum.
I just wanted to share this with you.
Ben sadece bunu seninle paylamak istedim.